<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>typescript on David Wesst</title>
    <link>https://davidwesst.com/tags/typescript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in typescript on David Wesst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 13:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidwesst.com/tags/typescript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>F12 Chooser is a Dev Tool Thing</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/f12-chooser-is-dev-tool-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/f12-chooser-is-dev-tool-thing/</guid>
      <description>The F12 Chooser is a development tool thing that I like and you should know about if you want your web application or web extension to support Microsoft Edge.
The F12 Developer Tools are pretty great. They are the original in-browser developer tools (included in Internet Explorer 7), and have evolved into something more modern for all us &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; developers.
With all in-browser developer tools, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that every once and I come across an application I&amp;rsquo;m trying to debug that is so unstable that F12 can&amp;rsquo;t seem to attache properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking between TypeScript and JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/typescript-or-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/typescript-or-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Which one should you pick: TypeScript or JavaScript? They are both great languages, people always ask me when you should use one or the other. This post puts that to rest.
Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a work project or a personal one, the question &amp;ldquo;TypeScript or JavaScript&amp;rdquo; always seems to come up in my mind. Utlimately, they provide a very similiar function considering that TypeScript is a superset of JavaScript, and compiles down to JavaScript itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing My Game Project - March 2017 Devblog</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/conquest-march-2017-devblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/conquest-march-2017-devblog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to make a video game since I was very young. It got me into programming during my university career, and is something of a passion of mine now that I&amp;rsquo;m older and more of a seasoned developer.
I&amp;rsquo;ve toyed and tinkered with different game ideas and technologies through the years, but never really got anything done. At the beginning of this year, I started working on something I decided would be my first &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Compile TypeScript into a Single File with SystemJS Modules with Gulp</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-compile-typescript-into-a-single-file-with-systemjs-modules-with-gulp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 09:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-compile-typescript-into-a-single-file-with-systemjs-modules-with-gulp/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around with TypeScript again for my game project and wanted a module loader to consume the single file produced by the TypeScript compiler. This time around I decided to use SystemJS and figured I&amp;rsquo;d share the lessons I learned along the way.
Sample Project If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in playing with the code, you can checkout this GitHub project I setup just for that reason.
Previous Post I also posted about doing the same sort of thing with AMD and RequireJS complete with a GitHub sample project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Thoughts on Using Phaser</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/new-post-initial-thoughts-on-phaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/new-post-initial-thoughts-on-phaser/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a game dev, but have always wanted to make a video game. I&amp;rsquo;ve started and stopped so many project over the years, that I have seriously lost count.
With the new year and a fresh mind, I decided to take a stab at it again, this time focusing on just getting something done rather than getting something done right as a sort of side project.
It&amp;rsquo;s been about two months since I&amp;rsquo;ve started, and I have something basic working (although I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to share it yet) and I thought I would share my thoughts on Phaser, the framework I decided to use to help me build my game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Not Required - The New Microsoft Development Story (Video)</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/windows-not-required-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 10:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/windows-not-required-video/</guid>
      <description>This is a recording of my recent Winnipeg .NET User Group talk about using Microsoft tools without requiring Windows.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the most technical as I go over a ton of topics, at high level, ranging from development tools, to applications. Still, I find this stuff really interesting and hopefully you enjoy it too.
You can view the slides here and find their source code here on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Compile Typescript into a Single File with AMD Modules with Gulp</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/typescript-with-amd-and-gulp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 08:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/typescript-with-amd-and-gulp/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with TypeScript lately and was trying to setup my project to compile all of my modules into a single file, which would then be used in an HTML page. Maybe this is obvious to the more experienced TypeScript developer, but I had made a number of false assumptions while trying to get this to work.
This post will walk you through what I did to setup my build and get it working in an HTML page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>