<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NodeJS on David Wesst</title>
    <link>https://davidwesst.com/tags/nodejs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NodeJS on David Wesst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 08:33:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidwesst.com/tags/nodejs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Global NPM Packages on a VSTS Self-Hosted Build Agent</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-use-global-npm-packages-on-a-vsts-self-hosted-build-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 08:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-use-global-npm-packages-on-a-vsts-self-hosted-build-agent/</guid>
      <description>I took a couple of weeks off of blogging to focus on a building my presentation for Deliver. In my spare time, I started tinkering with Visual Studio Team Services, where decided to start by automating the build and release of this blog.
My build script is pretty straight forward. Setup the global dependencies with NPM, setup the local dependencies with NPM, generate the content, and publish the generated assets. This worked in my hosted agent, but not my self-hosted agent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix node-gyp Error on Windows</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-fix-node-gyp-error-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 14:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-fix-node-gyp-error-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>I hit this problem once or twice a year and always seem to forget how easy it is to fix the problem. This blog post will ensure that not only I remember, but the entire Internet will remember the solution I use.
Here goes.
The Problem The problem is simple: You pull down a repository that uses NPM for package management onto your Windows machine, you type npm install and you get something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>