<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gulp on David Wesst</title>
    <link>https://davidwesst.com/tags/gulp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gulp on David Wesst</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 09:47:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidwesst.com/tags/gulp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build ReactJS with Gulp</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-build-reactjs-with-gulp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 19:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-build-reactjs-with-gulp/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to play with ReactJS last week and figured I would just add another gulp talk to my build process, being that it&amp;rsquo;s all the rage right now.
It turns out that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that simple, as it turns out that the gulp-react has been &amp;ldquo;deprecated in favor of gulp-babel&amp;rdquo;. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t planned on learning Babel, but it turns out it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very difficult once I was able to put all the pieces together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Compile Typescript into a Single File with AMD Modules with Gulp</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/typescript-with-amd-and-gulp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 08:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/typescript-with-amd-and-gulp/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with TypeScript lately and was trying to setup my project to compile all of my modules into a single file, which would then be used in an HTML page. Maybe this is obvious to the more experienced TypeScript developer, but I had made a number of false assumptions while trying to get this to work.
This post will walk you through what I did to setup my build and get it working in an HTML page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Highlight.Js with Bower and Gulp</title>
      <link>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-use-highlight-js-with-bower-and-gulp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 10:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidwesst.com/blog/how-to-use-highlight-js-with-bower-and-gulp/</guid>
      <description>One of the challenges I faced when getting my new blog theme up and running was getting highlight.js working as I wanted it to. The library has support for a riduculous number of languages, and provides theming capabilities, so it was the clear choice when it came to syntax highlighting for the web. The challenge is that tt&amp;rsquo;s not just adding simple script tag and you&amp;rsquo;re done with it. They seem to expect you to know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing when consuming the library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>